Chen Bulei diaries
Hoover Institution Archives
Chen Bulei diaries
1931-1948
2016C14
Hoover Institution Archives
3 manuscript boxes, 1 microfilm box (1.3 linear feet)
Relates to political and military conditions in China.
Chen, Bulei, 1890-1948
Location of Original Materials
Originals in possession of: Chen Di.
Access
The microfilm is closed. Use copies (Boxes 1-3) are available on-site for research.
Use copies may not be photocopied nor photographed; only handwritten notes may be taken.
Collection is served one folder at a time.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2016.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
Born in Zhejiang Province, Chen was best known as Chiang Kai-shek’s confidential assistant, in which position he phrased the policies of the Chinese Nationalist Party (KMT) and the Nationalist government. In the spring of 1926, Chen joined the newly established Nationalist government in Nanjing under the leadership of Chiang Kai-shek. Henceforth, he became Chiang’s personal assistant, mainly responsible for drafting state papers and speeches for the Generalissimo. In 1930 Chen was appointed vice minister of education; in 1934 he served in Chiang’s field headquarters in Nanchang, and then in 1935 he became director of the second department of the Generalissimo’s attendance office, where he served as Chiang’s confidential assistant for over a decade.
After China entered the war with Japan in 1937, Chen’s responsibilities grew, and Chiang Kai-shek made increasing use of Chen’s talent for phrasing the policies of the KMT and the Nationalist government and composing state papers for Chiang. In 1939, Chen was appointed deputy secretary general of the Supreme National Defense Council, the top organ of wartime China. The demands of the Japanese war period, combined with the deterioration of the Nationalist political position after 1945, drained Chen’s resources. He was greatly concerned by the expansion of Communist power and by the rising tide of criticism of Chiang Kai-shek, and he increasingly felt that his usefulness was spent.
On November 13, 1948, he took his own life with an overdose of sleeping drugs, leaving letters of explanation to his family, to Chiang Kai-shek, and to several close friends.
Scope and Contents note
The personal diaries of Chen Bulei cover the period from March 5, 1931, to November 11, 1948. These diaries witness one of the most turbulent periods in modern Chinese history. As Chiang Kai-shek’s confidential assistant throughout the Nationalist era on the Chinese mainland, these daily records provide crucial insider’s views on Nationalist China’s politics, party affairs, external relations, and war with Japan.
Related Collection(s)
Chiang Kai-Shek diaries, Hoover Institution Archives
Chiang, Kai-shek, 1887-1975.; China--History--Republic, 1912-1949.
- March, 1931 (Box-folder 1: 1)
- April, 1931 (Box-folder 1: 2)
- May, 1931 (Box-folder 1: 3)
- June, 1931 (Box-folder 1: 4)
- July, 1931 (Box-folder 1: 5)
- August, 1931 (Box-folder 1: 6)
- September, 1931 (Box-folder 1: 7)
- March, 1936 (Box-folder 1: 8)
- April, 1936 (Box-folder 1: 9)
- May, 1936 (Box-folder 1: 10)
- June, 1936 (Box-folder 1: 11)
- July, 1936 (Box-folder 1: 12)
- August, 1936 (Box-folder 1: 13)
- September, 1936 (Box-folder 1: 14)
- October, 1936 (Box-folder 1: 15)
- November, 1936 (Box-folder 1: 16)
- December, 1936 (Box-folder 1: 17)
- January, 1937 (Box-folder 1: 18)
- February, 1937 (Box-folder 1: 19)
- March, 1937 (Box-folder 1: 20)
- April, 1937 (Box-folder 1: 21)
- May, 1937 (Box-folder 1: 22)
- June, 1937 (Box-folder 1: 23)
- July, 1937 (Box-folder 1: 24)
- August, 1937 (Box-folder 1: 25)
- September, 1937 (Box-folder 1: 26)
- October, 1937 (Box-folder 1: 27)
- November, 1937 (Box-folder 1: 28)
- December, 1937 (Box-folder 1: 29)
- January, 1938 (Box-folder 1: 30)
- February, 1938 (Box-folder 1: 31)
- March, 1938 (Box-folder 1: 32)
- April, 1938 (Box-folder 1: 33)
- May, 1938 (Box-folder 1: 34)
- June, 1938 (Box-folder 1: 35)
- July, 1938 (Box-folder 1: 36)
- August, 1938 (Box-folder 1: 37)
- September, 1938 (Box-folder 1: 38)
- October, 1938 (Box-folder 1: 39)
- November, 1938 (Box-folder 1: 40)
- December, 1938 (Box-folder 1: 41)
- January, 1939 (Box-folder 1: 42)
- February, 1939 (Box-folder 1: 43)
- March, 1939 (Box-folder 1: 44)
- April, 1939 (Box-folder 1: 45)
- May, 1939 (Box-folder 1: 46)
- June, 1939 (Box-folder 1: 47)
- July, 1939 (Box-folder 1: 48)
- August, 1939 (Box-folder 1: 49)
- September, 1939 (Box-folder 1: 50)
- October, 1939 (Box-folder 1: 51)
- November, 1939 (Box-folder 1: 52)
- December, 1939 (Box-folder 1: 53)
- January, 1940 (Box-folder 2: 1)
- February, 1940 (Box-folder 2: 2)
- March, 1940 (Box-folder 2: 3)
- April, 1940 (Box-folder 2: 4)
- May, 1940 (Box-folder 2: 5)
- June, 1940 (Box-folder 2: 6)
- July, 1940 (Box-folder 2: 7)
- August, 1940 (Box-folder 2: 8)
- September, 1940 (Box-folder 2: 9)
- October, 1940 (Box-folder 2: 10)
- November, 1940 (Box-folder 2: 11)
- December, 1940 (Box-folder 2: 12)
- January, 1941 (Box-folder 2: 13)
- February, 1941 (Box-folder 2: 14)
- March, 1941 (Box-folder 2: 15)
- April, 1941 (Box-folder 2: 16)
- May, 1941 (Box-folder 2: 17)
- June, 1941 (Box-folder 2: 18)
- July, 1941 (Box-folder 2: 19)
- August, 1941 (Box-folder 2: 20)
- September, 1941 (Box-folder 2: 21)
- October, 1941 (Box-folder 2: 22)
- November, 1941 (Box-folder 2: 23)
- December, 1941 (Box-folder 2: 24)
- January, 1942 (Box-folder 2: 25)
- February, 1942 (Box-folder 2: 26)
- March, 1942 (Box-folder 2: 27)
- April, 1942 (Box-folder 2: 28)
- May, 1942 (Box-folder 2: 29)
- June, 1942 (Box-folder 2: 30)
- July, 1942 (Box-folder 2: 31)
- August, 1942 (Box-folder 2: 32)
- September, 1942 (Box-folder 2: 33)
- October, 1942 (Box-folder 2: 34)
- November, 1942 (Box-folder 2: 35)
- December, 1942 (Box-folder 2: 36)
- January, 1943 (Box-folder 2: 37)
- February, 1943 (Box-folder 2: 38)
- March, 1943 (Box-folder 2: 39)
- April, 1943 (Box-folder 2: 40)
- May, 1943 (Box-folder 2: 41)
- June, 1943 (Box-folder 2: 42)
- July, 1943 (Box-folder 2: 43)
- August, 1943 (Box-folder 2: 44)
- September, 1943 (Box-folder 2: 45)
- October, 1943 (Box-folder 2: 46)
- November, 1943 (Box-folder 2: 47)
- December, 1943 (Box-folder 2: 48)
- January, 1944 (Box-folder 2: 49)
- February, 1944 (Box-folder 2: 50)
- March, 1944 (Box-folder 2: 51)
- April, 1944 (Box-folder 2: 52)
- May, 1944 (Box-folder 2: 53)
- June, 1944 (Box-folder 2: 54)
- July, 1944 (Box-folder 2: 55)
- August, 1944 (Box-folder 2: 56)
- September, 1944 (Box-folder 2: 57)
- October, 1944 (Box-folder 2: 58)
- November, 1944 (Box-folder 2: 59)
- December, 1944 (Box-folder 2: 60)
- January, 1945 (Box-folder 3: 1)
- February, 1945 (Box-folder 3: 2)
- March, 1945 (Box-folder 3: 3)
- April, 1945 (Box-folder 3: 4)
- May, 1945 (Box-folder 3: 5)
- June, 1945 (Box-folder 3: 6)
- July, 1945 (Box-folder 3: 7)
- August, 1945 (Box-folder 3: 8)
- September, 1945 (Box-folder 3: 9)
- October, 1945 (Box-folder 3: 10)
- November, 1945 (Box-folder 3: 11)
- December, 1945 (Box-folder 3: 12)
- January, 1946 (Box-folder 3: 13)
- February, 1946 (Box-folder 3: 14)
- March, 1946 (Box-folder 3: 15)
- April, 1946 (Box-folder 3: 16)
- May, 1946 (Box-folder 3: 17)
- June, 1946 (Box-folder 3: 18)
- July, 1946 (Box-folder 3: 19)
- August, 1946 (Box-folder 3: 20)
- September, 1946 (Box-folder 3: 21)
- October, 1946 (Box-folder 3: 22)
- November, 1946 (Box-folder 3: 23)
- December, 1946 (Box-folder 3: 24)
- January, 1947 (Box-folder 3: 25)
- February, 1947 (Box-folder 3: 26)
- March, 1947 (Box-folder 3: 27)
- April, 1947 (Box-folder 3: 28)
- May, 1947 (Box-folder 3: 29)
- June, 1947 (Box-folder 3: 30)
- July, 1947 (Box-folder 3: 31)
- August, 1947 (Box-folder 3: 32)
- September, 1947 (Box-folder 3: 33)
- October, 1947 (Box-folder 3: 34)
- November, 1947 (Box-folder 3: 35)
- December, 1947 (Box-folder 3: 36)
- January, 1948 (Box-folder 3: 37)
- February, 1948 (Box-folder 3: 38)
- March, 1948 (Box-folder 3: 39)
- April, 1948 (Box-folder 3: 40)
- May, 1948 (Box-folder 3: 41)
- June, 1948 (Box-folder 3: 42)
- July, 1948 (Box-folder 3: 43)
- August, 1948 (Box-folder 3: 44)
- September, 1948 (Box-folder 3: 45)
- October, 1948 (Box-folder 3: 46)
- November, 1948 (Box-folder 3: 47)